# Bryan O. Aniekwena

7943 Hanging Branch San Antonio, Texas, 78253 (210) 519-9073; banie@allstate.com Webpage: https://bedmac.github.io

# **Submission Summary**

#### High-yield, High-performing, Claims Specialist:

Skilled and thorough in analyzing problems, situations, while finding effective, and creative solutions. Strengths include Production, Efficiency, Customer service, Content Development, Digital Strategies, and Application Design. Have been at least top 10 in Production, CLF, Field Settle-Onsite, and Digital Pay for the last multiple years on resource 200.

## Applying for Claim Service Leader Position.

## **Core Qualifications**

#### Software Skill Set

**Advanced:** Xactimate, XactAnalysis, ClaimsX, NextGen, Claims Process Tool, Microsoft Cloud, Microsoft Office, Windows Troubleshooting

Intermediate: Java, Python, C, C++, PHP, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Android Studio, Word Press.

#### Hardware Skill Set

PC and Android troubleshooting, installation, Cable, Soldering, Networking, and Circuit Analysis.

**Superior problem-solving skills:** Ability to work well under pressure and meet deadlines. Extremely punctual and flexible. Efficiency, metrics, and production powerhouse.

# **Education / Training**

Institute of Inspection Cleaning and Restoration Certification (Certification Date: November 2023) IICRC WRT Certification

The University of Texas at San Antonio (Graduation Date: May 2018)

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with a concentration in Software Engineering

**Some of the Coursework includes** System/Network Security, Applications Programming, Systems Programming, Microprocessors, C++ and Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Analysis of Algorithms, Advanced Software Engineering, Software Enterprise, Machine Learning, Object-Orientated Systems, and Computer Networks.

### **Professional Experience**

Senior Claims Service Adjuster Allstate – Countrywide, USA June 2018 – Present

- In-person Post-NEO Recap Trainer at the DFW Pilot facility TDY. (January 2024 Present).
- 207 Team Lead (2020 Present)
- Field Ride Along Mentor (2019 Present)
- CEA Super Huddle Facilitator (March 2023)
- R200 Employee of the month (June 2022)
- Administrative support throughout my team and resource.
  - o Run overdue pending, tasks, and Xactimate Reports.
  - Handle escalation call requests
  - o Coach and recognize team members
  - o Run Daily CLF report for my resource

Page 2

Web Admin/ Undergraduate Research Assistant at the Child and Adolescent Policy Research Institute The University of Texas at San Antonio – San Antonio, TX October 2015 – January 2018

- Webpage Development and IT support.
- Conduct social science research and literature review through scholarly, scientific investigations and research training.
- Conduct research public policies and issues related to cross-disciplinary fields of study related to child and adolescent development and community-based activities
- Accounting, which includes various expense forms, Reconciliation reports, and auditing.
- Initiated and completed projects accurately with deadlines
- Administrative support throughout the department

HVAC/Ice Plant Maintenance Helper SeaWorld San Antonio – San Antonio, TX July 2010 – January 2018

- Sold, packaged, and delivered ice throughout the park.
- Managed Other Team Members
- Assist HVAC Shop with maintenance and service
- Worked as part of the technical trades team to increase productivity while providing excellent guest service

Premises Technician AT&T – San Antonio, TX December 2014 – February 2015

- Educated Customers on service features and functionality
- Verify all services are working correctly, and if not fix
- Installation and rearrange inside wires
- Sold AT&T services and upgrades

Library Assistant John Jay High School – San Antonio, TX August 2009 – May 2010

- Assisted librarian and our quests with a variety of needs, i.e.: information finding, and technical support
- Cataloged, using various software and technologies

# **Activities and Affiliations**

Member in the National Honors Society John Jay Science and Engineering Academy - San Antonio, TX 2008 – Present

- Organized community service projects on large scale, which included events, social gathering, and
- Took part in several volunteer projects.
- Took several different classes on a variety of topics
- Maintained equipment
- Learned leadership, responsibility, several useful skills

Member in the UTSA Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)

# **Bryan Aniekwena**

Page 3

University of Texas at San Antonio – San Antonio, TX 2010 – 2012

Volunteer St. Rose of Lima Church – San Antonio, Texas 2009-2010

• 90+ Community Service hours

# **Projects**

SCRUM Master/Project leader Patient Portal Spring 2017

Website: https://patientportal.comeze.com

The PATIENT PORTAL is a web application that manages electronic patient records to provide rapid and efficient means to handle medical information of a clinic. Traditionally, a clinic uses paper-based patient records, which are expensive and take up space to maintain. Moreover, filing, retrieval of, and re-filing paper patient records are more labor intensive and less efficient compared to the electronic patient records. Using the PATIENT PORTAL shall alleviate these problems. The overall goal of the PATIENT PORTAL is to provide physicians, nurses, and clinical staff with a powerful, easy-to-use tool that securely assists them in gathering, storing, and manipulating Patients' information.

- Developed in PHP
- Used MySQL databases
- Included User Profiles
- Easy to maintain
- Secure

Web Admin/Developer Child and Adolescent Policy Research Institute and The UTSA Mexico Center Summer 2017

Websites: http://capri.utsa.edu/ http://mxcenter.utsa.edu/

The Child and Adolescent Policy Research Institute and The Mexico Center needed a new Website and I was in charge of creating it. Using WordPress and with some help from Giles-Parscale and The University of Texas at San Antonio's Office of Information Technology. I was able to completely renovate their old site. I had to maintain constant communications with all parties involved (UTSA, CAPRI Administration, and Giles-Parscale).

- CMS WordPress
- PHP, CSS, and HTML
- Easy to maintain
- Very User Friendly

Developer/Tester Android Application- LawnTech Summer 2017

An android app which allows homeowners to connect with lawn mower workers. Both sides should be able to rate each other. The app will allow both side to see the location (within map overview) and time range (after request the mower) of the service, and decide on an appropriate price (to be determined by stakeholder). This will allow mowers to find business and upon their own hours.

# **Bryan Aniekwena** Page 4

- Android Application
- Database
- GPS
- Personal, Customizable, Accounts